Kiruthikapoorani. A

Professional Summary

Highly effective software developer offering a wealth of 7 years of expertise. A valuable team player who also is personable and dedicated. Seeking the chance to bring further success to an established organization through testing, deployment, and software debugging.

Academic Qualification

2014 B.Tech. (Information Technology) from Dr. Mahalingam College of Engg & Technology, Pollachi, Affiliated to Anna University with an aggregate of 80%.

2010 Diploma (Information Technology) from Nachimuthu Polytechnic College, Pollachi with97.7%.

Technical Skill Set

Languages : Python, Java (basic)

• Reporting Package : RML, SQL with XML view, SQL with PDFview, Qweb

Database System : PostgreSQL, MySQL

Web Technologies : HTML, XML, JavaScript, CSS

Platforms Used : Ubuntu and Windows

Certification : Odoo15 Functional Certification

Work Experience

Project Manager From March 2022 OODU Implementers Pvt. Ltd Coimbatore, India

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Worked in API Integration with JSON RPC & XML RPC calls through REST / SOAP integration.
- Handled many servers and worked on the project live support.
- · Worked on various website functionalities.
- Worked as Techno functional till Odoo 16 and handled team of 20 members.
- · Worked as a technical trainer.
- Activity and Resource planning for the team.
- Preparing cost estimation and budget for the project.
- Handled more than 8 customers for the functional and technical support.

Project Lead March 2019 to February 2022 Rminds Development Centre, LLP Pune, India

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Worked on integration of Fax, S3 Attachment storage, Fedex with Odoo 12.
- Worked on natural language processing in Python and various libraries.
- · Worked on various levels and types of file handling.
- Worked on US Accounting sector and various reports.
- Handled many servers and worked on the project live support.
- Worked in API Integration with JSON RPC & XML RPC calls through REST / SOAP integration.
- Worked on various encryption methods to store secure Data.

- Worked on various website functionalities.
- Worked as Techno functional till Odoo 15 and handled team of 20 members.

Senior Technical Consultant

February 2017 to February 2019

(2 years)

Coimbatore, India

Itara IT Solutions Pvt. Ltd

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Developed application from scratch.
- Web API's, Magento Integration for Odoo 11 Enterprise.
- External Tool Integration, SMS Integrations.
- Debug existing source code and polish feature sets.
- Take up the responsibility of the entire Project and handled team of 10 members.
- Provided technical guidance and coaching to developers, and conducted code review.
- Worked in various odoo modules like Sales, Purchase, CRM, Accounts, Inventory, Projects, Timesheet, HR etc

Technical Consultant

January 2016 to January 2017

(1 year 1 month)

Coimbatore, India

AST IT Solutions Pvt. Ltd

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Designed and implemented solutions on time and within budget while delivering high quality services.
- Have good knowledge in Odoo(OpenERP) Sale, Purchase, Warehouse, HR and Project fundamental flows.
- Have knowledge in Controllers and Web Sale modules.
- Have knowledge in RML reports, PostgreSQL reports and Qweb reports.

Software Developer

May2014 toMarch 2015

Amachu Automations

Pollachi, India

Roles and Responsibilities:

 Gained working knowledge about Odoo basics, Python basics, SQL like basic SQL queries, Constraints, Triggers and Procedures & Functions.

Other Professional Skills

- Problem solving capability
- Good leadership skills
- Ability to complete task intime.
- Have interest and faith in Team Work.
- Adaptable to the surroundings.

I hereby declare that the details given above are true to the best of my knowledge.